Jennifer Herr

Jenh11@gmail.com | https://linkedin.com/in/jenh11

Summary

Professional with 15 years of experience as a police officer, detective and 911 emergency phone operator transitioning to a career in web development. Self-starter who created and developed a youth leadership program with 15 youth and 6 adult advisors enrolled, and managed it to achieve over 200% increases in membership enrollment and participation metrics within the first year. Passionate about learning and improving, and being a positive force for good.

SKILLS

- Team Leadership
- Strategic Thinking & Planning
- Relationship Building
- Verbal & Written Communication

- Process Evaluation & Improvement
- Problem Solving
- Time Management
- Conflict Resolution

EXPERIENCE

Program Manager | Lead Advisor

Mar 2018 - Present

Sammamish Police Explorers, Sammamish, Washington

- Started youth leadership program with a partner to build relationships between community and law enforcement
 - Drove recruiting efforts to achieve a 260% increase in program enrollment in the first 6 months and 530% program enrollment since inception
 - Sustained program enrollment and participation numbers to achieve goals of 15 youth actively involved providing more than 400 community service volunteer hours per quarter post-COVID
 - Achieved a 2nd place and two 3rd place trophies in statewide competition between more than 20 programs with over 15 scored events
- Conceptualized and documented all program processes with an eye on continuous process improvement
 - Designed and developed 6 unique spreadsheet systems to track program operations to improve workflow and accountability
 - Created standard process for recruit assessment and onboarding; successfully screened, interviewed, and inducted over 30 youth applicants
- Developed and maintained relationships with stakeholders from internal and external programs and organizations
 - Acquired donation worth \$10,000 to solve transportation issue by developing and leveraging external relationship with an elected official
 - Produced opportunities resulting in 3000 volunteer hours worked last year, representing a 230% increase in community service hours worked since inception

- Maintained ownership of task delegation, tracking and progression for up to 20 tasks for a cross-functional project team of 4 youth and 5 adults
- Developed and executed strategies to keep youth engaged during COVID-19 lockdowns;
 achieved a 44% membership increase while other programs lost members or shut down entirely

Deputy Sheriff Mar 2012 - Present

King County Sheriff's Office, Seattle, Washington

- Resolved a wide range of emergent and non-emergent incidents on a daily basis both individually and while operating in a 2-5 person team
- Operated under pressure calmly and with confidence to execute good decisions
- Commended 8 times for activities related to teamwork, collaboration, and team communication
- Commended 6 times for writing exceptionally effective investigative and incident reports

Detective Oct 2016 - Mar 2020

King County Sheriff's Office, Sammamish, Washington

- Collaborated with partners from local, regional, and federal teams during complex investigations to plan, coordinate and execute successful strategies
- Allocated time to triage and investigate up to 40 concurrent open cases with a filing success rate of 91%; most productive and efficient work rate within 4-person team
- Lead four different large-scale projects to solve complex problems resulting in crime reduction by more than 50% in each case

Communications Specialist

Mar 2006 - Jun 2010

King County Sheriff's Office, Seattle, Washington

 Processed emergency and non-emergency calls based on standardized operation procedures in a high-stress, high-volume call center

EDUCATION

Google Project Management Professional Certification

Mar 2022

Coursera

Master of Science (M.S.) – Criminology with Leadership Emphasis

Jan 2018 - Aug 2020

Regis University, Denver, Colorado

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.) - Psychology with minor in English

Western Washington University, Bellingham, WA